Employment Collection, 1817-1991 (bulk 1920-1976)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES VI. ACADEMIC WOMEN
  - Historians (Box 27)
    - Berkshire Conference of Women Historians 1976-83 (Box 27a, Folder 3)
    - Caucus of Women in History: newsletter 1973-75 (Box 27a, Folder 4)
    - Conference Group in Women's History 1975-77 (Box 27a, Folder 5)
    - Coordinating Committee on Women in the Historical Profession 1970-89 (Box 27a, Folder 6)
    - New England Association of Women Historians 1973-75 (Box 27a, Folder 7)
    - Organization of American Historians: newsletter 1973-75 (Box 27a, Folder 8)
    - Southern Association of Women Historians 1976-1991 (Box 27a, Folder 9)
    - Upstate New York Women's History Conference 1981-86 (Box 27a, Folder 10)
    - Western Association of Women Historians 1982-85 (Box 27a, Folder 11)
    - Women Historians of the Midwest (Newsletter) 1985-90 (Box 27a)
    - "Women Historian Attend Graduate School"1975 (Box 27a, Folder 12)
  - Organizations 1965-77 (Box 27a)
    - Modern Language Association (Box 27a)
      - Commission on the Status of Women (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Women's Caucus (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - National Council of Administrative Women in Education (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - American Council on Education, Office of Women in Higher Education (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Psychologists for Social Action (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - College Art Association (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - National Coalition for Research on Women's Education and Development (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Legal and legislative materials 1971-81 (Box 28)
    - Sex discrimination, academic institutions, and the law (Box 28a, Folder 1)
    - Louisiana State University (Carol Parr) (Box 28a, Folder 2)
    - University of California (Box 28a, Folder 3)
    - University of Pittsburgh (Sharon Johnson) (Box 28a, Folder 4)
    - Sex discrimination: executive orders, federal rules, etc. (Box 28a, Folder 5)
    - Higher Education Guidelines, Executive Order 11246 1972 (Box 28a, Folder 6)
    - "Women's Work Has Just Begun: Legal Problems of Employing Women in Universities," undated (Box 28a, Folder 7)
  - Articles, pamphlets and reports (Box 28a)
    - General 1924-29, 1970-80 (Box 29, Folder 1-4)
    - Programs and conferences 1973-79 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Teaching Faculty in Academe, 1972-73 by Alan Bayer 1973 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - College and University Faculty: A Statistical Description June 1970 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Careers of PhDs: Academic vs. Non-Academic, National Academy of Sciences 1968 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Degrees conferred 1968-69 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Availability Pools as the Basis for Affirmative Action by Lucy W. Sells 1973 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Status of Women in Higher Education: A Selective Bibliography 1972 (Box 29)
    - Women in the University of Chicago: Report of the Committee on University Women 1970 (Box 29)
  - Professional organizations 1969-81 (Box 29)
    - Association of American Colleges (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - AAUW (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - American Mathematical Society (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - American Philological Society, Women's Caucus (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - American Philosophical Association (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - American Political Science Association (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - American Psychological Association (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - American Studies Association (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Association for Women Psychologists (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Modern Language Association (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - National Association for Women Deans, Administrators, and Counselors (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - National Council of Administrative Women in Education (Box 30)
      - General (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - "News"1973-78 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Subjects 1970-76 (Box 30)
    - Bibliographies 1970-73, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Conferences 1970-76, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence 1970-71, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Nepotism and faculty wives 1972, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Part-time faculty 1972, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Periodicals 1971-72 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Retirement plans 1972 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Unions 1975 (Box 31, Folder 8)
- SERIES VII. COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
  - University of Akron 1970 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - American International College 1971 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Amherst College undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Bowling Green State College 1972 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Brandeis University 1971 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Brown University 1977 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - University of California at Berkeley 1970-73 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - University of California at Los Angeles 1972 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University 1971 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - University of Chicago 1969-70 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - City University of New York 1972 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Columbia University 1970-72, undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Dartmouth University 1972 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Douglass College 1970 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Duke University 1972 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Eastern Washington State College 1972 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Five Colleges, Inc. (Smith, Mount Holyoke, etc.)1971-76, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Five College Women, History 1971, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Florida State University 1970 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - University of South Florida 1970-73, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Proposal for an Affirmative Action Plan for Women at the University of South Florida 1972 (Box 33)
  - Hampshire College 1971 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Harvard University 1970-75, undated (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign 1970 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Indiana State University 1971 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Indiana University at Bloomington 1971 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - University of Massachusetts at Amherst 1970-72, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - University of Massachusetts at Boston (Salzman Case) 1971-72, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - University of Michigan 1971, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Michigan State University 1970 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Ohio State University 1970-71 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - University of Pennsylvania 1971-74 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Pennsylvania State University 1971 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - University of Pittsburgh 1970-71 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Princeton University 1971-73 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Rutgers University undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Seven College Conference undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Smith College 1957-75, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Stanford University 1971 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - University of Texas at Austin 1971 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Tufts University 1970-71, undated (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - University of Washington 1971 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Williams College 1970-71, undated (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - University of Wisconsin-Madison 1971-74, undated (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Yale University 1971-1976, undated (Box 34, Folder 19)
- SERIES VIII. ARMED SERVICES AND AVIATION
  - Armed Services (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, pamphlets, articles and clippings 1854-1977 (Box 35, Folder 1-3)
    - United States (Box 35)
      - Bibliographies, pamphlets, and articles 1943, 1977, undated (Box 35, Folder 3a)
      - The Female Marine, or the Adventures of Miss Lucy Brewer 1817 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Revolution and Civil War 1841-1971 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - World War I (Box 35)
        - Veterans 1924-25 (Box 35, Folder 6)
        - Memorials 1923-76 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - World War II 1952-57 (Box 35, Folder 8)
        - Mildred McAfee Horton 1944 (Box 35, Folder 9)
        - "The Position of Women in the U.S. Armed Forces Dec. 4, 1944," by Judy Angevin, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Post-World War II 1955-72 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - England: World War II 1942-47 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Aviation (Box 35)
    - Aerospace 1959-83 (Box 35a, Folder 1)
    - Jerrie Cobb 1973-74 (Box 35a, Folder 2)
    - Amelia Earhart 1930-75 (Box 35a, Folder 3)
    - Flight-related professions 1940-81 (Box 35a, Folder 4)
    - U.S.: general 1912-82 (Box 35a, Folder 5)
    - International Women in Aviation 1926-73 (Box 35a, Folder 6)
    - Amy Johnson 1930-32 (Box 35a, Folder 7)
    - Ruth Nichols 1930-72 (Box 35a, Folder 8)
    - Women Air Force Service Pilots (WASPs) (World War II) 1973-82 (Box 35a, Folder 9)
- SERIES IX. GOVERNMENT AND POLITICS
  - General 1894, 1972-75 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Women Elected to Boston School Committee, 1875-1977 1976 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Women's Campaign Fund 1974-79 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Individuals (Box 36)
    - Bella Abzug 1971-78 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Bertha Adkins circa 1958 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Eugenie Anderson 1952-57 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Lucille Atcherson 1923-25 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Charlotta Bass 1952 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Carol Bellamy 1978-79 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Lucy Wilson Benson 1966-78 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Marie Cole Berger undated (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Emily Blair 1924-51 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Yvonne Braithwaite Burke 1974-75 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Carol Burris 1975 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Mary L. Bynum 1929 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Hattie Caraway 1931-50 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Gudrun Carlson 1929 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Melnea Cass 1973 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Anne Cox Chambers 1978 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Shirley Chisholm 1970-72 (Box 36, Folder 20-21)
    - Georgia Clark 1950 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Margaret Costanza 1977-78 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Eleanor Lansing Dulles 1959 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - India Edwards 1952 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Frances Farenthold 1971-77 (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Millicent Fenwick 1975 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Miriam Ferguson 1925, undated (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Geraldine Ferraro, [see Oversized materials] (Box 36)
    - Pattie Field 1925, undated (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Ella Grasso 1974-76 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Martha Griffiths 1970 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Katie Hanna 1974 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Margaret Hanna 1937 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Patricia Roberts Harris 1971 (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Margaret Heckler 1972 (Box 36a, Folder 1)
    - Eva Hester 1974 (Box 36a, Folder 2)
    - Louise Day Hicks 1970-76 (Box 36a, Folder 3)
    - Oveta Culp Hobby undated (Box 36a, Folder 4)
    - Katherine Graham Howard 1954 (Box 36a, Folder 5)
    - Elizabeth Humes 1930 (Box 36a, Folder 6)
    - Linda Jenness 1971 (Box 36a, Folder 7)
    - Janet Johnston 1973 (Box 36a, Folder 8)
    - Barbara Jordon 1974-79 (Box 36a, Folder 9)
    - Florence Prag Kahn 1927-31 (Box 36a, Folder 10)
    - Florence Knapp 1924-26 (Box 36a, Folder 11)
    - Juanita Kreps 1977 (Box 36a, Folder 12)
    - Bertha Landes 1926-28 (Box 36a, Folder 13)
    - Abigail McCarthy 1977 (Box 36a, Folder 14)
    - Ruth McCormick 1927-30 (Box 36a, Folder 15)
    - Carmen Magmi 1973 (Box 36a, Folder 16)
    - Barbara Mikulski 1973-74 (Box 36a, Folder 17)
    - Maya Miller undated (Box 36a, Folder 18)
    - Alice Moyer-Wing 1926-28 (Box 36a, Folder 19)
    - Bess Myerson 1970-73 (Box 36a, Folder 20)
    - Pat Nixon 1970 (Box 36a, Folder 21)
    - Elaine Noble 1974 (Box 36a, Folder 22)
    - Mary T. Norton 1924-33 (Box 36a, Folder 23)
    - Ruth Bryan Owen 1928-33 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Frances Perkins 1893-1934 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Ruth Baker Pratt 1925-30 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Jeanette Rankin 1916-73 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Alice Roberston 1922-31 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Edith Rogers 1924-41 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Lenore Romney 1971 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Nellie Ross 1925-77 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Susanna Salter 1955-56 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Marg Smith 1972-75 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Benetta Washington 1971 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Sarah Weddington 1979 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Katherine Elkus White 1964 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Mabel Willebrandt 1924-29 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Frances Willis 1955-60 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - England and Europe (Box 37)
    - Parliament 1924-71 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Lady Astor 1921-64 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Women in government service 1929-72 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Margaret Bond Field 1919-29 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Dame Rachel Gowdy 1926 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Marjorie Spikes 1945-46 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Margaret Thatcher 1975-79 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Ellen Wilkinson 1934-47 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Europe: general 1925-78 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - United States (Box 37)
    - "National Directory of Women Elected Officials"1981 (Box 38)
    - "Government Action: What Women Want," Nation Women's 'Speak Out' Seminar 1975 (Box 38)
    - Women in politics: General (including Democratic and Republican Party publications) (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Women's role in politics 1948-81 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Women on American Politics: Selected Bibliography (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Candidates: miscellaneous undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Presidential candidates (Box 38)
      - General 1957-2000 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Victoria C. Woodhull 1956-71 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Women in1928 presidential campaign, 1928 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Political campaigns 1972 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Geraldine Ferraro 1982 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Women in public office: National League of Women Voters surveys 1933, 1937 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Members of Congress 1921-79 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Government officials 1950-51 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Local officials 1914-79 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Civil Service 1937-75 (Box 38a, Folder 1)
      - Republican National Committee Surveys 1953, 1955 (Box 38a, Folder 2)
      - Federally Employed Women, Inc.: "News and Views"1979-80 (Box 38a, Folder 3)
    - Women in the CIA 1975-78 (Box 38a, Folder 4)
    - Executive Protective Service 1970 (Box 38a, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare 1971 (Box 38a, Folder 6)
    - Women in Foreign Service (Box 38a)
      - General 1925-71 (Box 38a, Folder 7)
      - Ambassadors 1965-76 (Box 38a, Folder 8)
    - Women in American foreign affairs 1977 (Box 38a)
    - Newspaper clippings 1914-81 (Box 38b, Folder 1-7)
- SERIES X. LABOR LEADERS
  - "I am a Woman Worker": A Scrapbook of Autobiographies (Affiliated Schools for Workers, Inc.) 1936 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - General 1926-79 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Labor Heroines: Ten Women Who Led the Struggle by Joyce Maupin (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, Mary L. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Cohn, Fannia 1927-28 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Coit, Eleanor 1962 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Davis, Caroline 1960-61 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Dewson, Mary 1934, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Faithfull, Emily 1861 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Mason, Lucy Randolph 1952-59 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Lang, Lucy Robbins 1950-57 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    [see also Oversized materials]
  - Pesotta, Rose 1958 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Robins, Margaret Dreier (Box 39)
    - General 1921 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins by Mary E. Dreier 1950 (Box 39)
  - Smith, Moranda 1951, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Stokes, Rose Pastor 1933 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Troup, Augusta Lewis 1920 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - van Kleeck, Mary (Box 39, Folder 17)
    [see also Mary van Kleeck Papers]
  - Wootton, Barbara 1925 (Box 39, Folder 18)
- SERIES XI. LAW
  - General 1920-83 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Clippings 1892-1979 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Prose: National Law Women's Newsletter 1970-72 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Judges 1931-79 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Women admitted to Massachusetts Bar 1900-25 (list) (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Bell, Mabel Van Dyke 1912 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Bittenbender, Ada M. 1882-91 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Bradwell, Myra Colby 1894, undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Helen 1950 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Burlingame, Lettie undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Foster, Judith undated (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - France 1927-28, undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Gordon, Laura deForce undated (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Greene, Mary A. 1888 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Hall, Mary 1882 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Kane, Kate Kane undated (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Kenyon, Dorothy 1948-66 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    [see also Dorothy Kenyon Papers]
  - Kilgore, Carrie Burnham 1908, undated (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - King, Angie J. undated (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Kross, Anna Moscowitz 1958 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    [see also Anna Moscowitz Kross Papers]
  - LeValley, Florence E. 1890 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Lockwood, Belva 1879-1981 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Lounsbury, Leona 1881 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Martin, Leonora 1889 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - McCullock, Catherine Waugh 1888-1945 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Mussey, Ellen 1919 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Normanton, Helena 1925 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Norris, Jean H. 1919, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Parker, Alice undated (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Ricker, Marilla 1882 (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - Robinson, Lelia 1850, undated (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - Rohleder, Grace 1920 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Sampson, Edith 1968 (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - Sassower, Doris 1978-79, undated (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - Sellers, Kathryn 1925 (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - Simon, Caroline 1957-58 (Box 40, Folder 36)
  - Southworth, Anne undated (Box 40, Folder 37)
  - Springer, Ada Lee undated (Box 40, Folder 38)
  - Todd, Marion 1886, undated (Box 40, Folder 39)
  - Volner, Jill 1974 (Box 40, Folder 40)
  - Wagstaff, Flora Torrey 1882 (Box 40, Folder 41)
  - Waite, Catherine 1886 (Box 40, Folder 42)
  - Willebrandt, Mabel Walker 1925-28 (Box 40, Folder 43)
  - Wing, Marie 1960 (Box 40, Folder 44)
- SERIES XII. SCIENCES
  - Bibliographies 1974 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Articles 1915-76 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets 1903-77 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Clippings 1924-78 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Women in Science by Gladys Anslow undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Women in Science by Judith Garelick undated (1980?) (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Association of Women in Science 1972-73 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Astronomy (Box 41)
    - General 1921-60 (Box 41, Folder 8-9)
    - Maria Mitchell 1857-1949 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Ida Barney undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Astronauts 1962-77 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Biology 1939-80 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Botany (Box 41)
    - Amalie Dietrich undated (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Emily J. Leonard 1885 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Kate Furbish 1977 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Chemistry (Box 41)
    - General 1922-57 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Marie Curie 1903-67 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Anna Harrison 1977 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Dorothy Hodgkin 1964 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Engineering: Maria Telkes 1948-49 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Entomology: Elizabeth Dorr 1833, undated (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - History of Science: C. Doris Hellman 1960 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Limnology: Ruth Patrick 1958-62 (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Mathematics: Mary Fairfax Somerville, 132-1978 (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Microbiology (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Elizabeth McCoy 1976 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Mary Ann Booth undated (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Naturalists (Box 41)
    - Anna Comstock 1924, 1930 (Box 41a, Folder 1)
    - Maria Merian 1962 (Box 41a, Folder 2)
  - Physics: Maria Mayer undated (Box 41a, Folder 3)
  - Physiology: Ida Hyde undated (Box 41a, Folder 4)
  - Poultry science: Marie Gutowska undated (Box 41a, Folder 5)
  - Relativity: Mary Milbank Brown 1948, undated (Box 41a, Folder 6)
  - Veterinary science 1972 (Box 41a, Folder 7)
  - Women in technological history 1979 (Box 41a, Folder 8)
- SERIES XIII. SOCIAL WORK AND PHILANTHROPY
  [see also Box 42a]
  - Social work: general 1940-70 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Clippings 1914-74 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Kelley, Florence 1887-1964 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Moffat, Adeline1956 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Wald, Lilian 1938-71 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Social Work, Special Issue on Women, Vol. 21, No. 6, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Abbott, Grace 1939 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Binford, Jessie 1966 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Carpenter, Mary 1879 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Social workers in politics 1963-64 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Hincks, Anne Perry 1955, undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Davis, Katharine Bement 1928 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Lowell, Josephine 1932, undated (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - McDowell, Mary undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - MacDonald, A. Caroline 1931 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - McMain, Eleanor undated (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Moskowitz, Belle Linddner 1932-1933 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Oettinger, Katherine 1957 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Reynolds, Bertha Capen (Box 42, Folder 20)
    [see also Bertha Capen Reynolds Papers]
  - Richmond, Mary E. 1929 (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Soman, Shirley Camper 1977, undated (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Philanthropy: general 1854-59 (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Bowen, Louise DeKoven (Box 42)
    - General 1945-53 (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Photographs 1950, undated (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - The Training School for Jewish Social Work Course Catalog1926-1937 (Box 42a)
- SERIES XIV. TRADE UNIONS
  - General 1924-80, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Organizing 1983 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - First New York trade union women's studies conference, Proceedings 1974 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Women and trade unions in the U.S. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - National Women's Trade Union League (NWTUL) (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Conventions 1909-36 (Box 43, Folder 6-8)
    - Publications 1919-53, undated (Box 43, Folder 9-10)
  - Individuals and specific unions (Box 43)
    - General 1919-80 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Working Women and Their Organizations: 150 Years of Struggle, Joyce Maupin 1974 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Leonora Marie Barry Lake 1886-89, 1976, undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Margaret Haley: photograph (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Emma Lamphere: photograph (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Agnes Nestor: photograph (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Emma Steghagen: photograph (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Anna Westergaard 1952, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - American Federation of Labor undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - American Newspaper Guild undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - ILGWU 1936-75 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - National Association of Working Women: "9 to 5"1982-83, 1989, undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - International Union of Hotel and Restaurant Workers: Hotel Northampton 1958-59 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Women's Trade Union League of Chicago 1908-44 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Working Women's Protective Union 1879-90 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Fabian Research Department (Women in the Engineering Trades by Barbara Drake 1917 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - International Charter of Labor (International Trade Union Conference, 1918, No. 3) 1939, undated (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers 1952-54 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - First Conference of Women Trade Unionists (Souvenir Program) 1964 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - New York Typographical Union, No. 6, undated (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - UAW Women's Bureau 1953-65 (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - Handbook for Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers 1973 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - Progressive Miners of America, Women's Auxiliary undated (Box 44a, Folder 23)
    - Transport Workers Union of America undated (1937?) (Box 44a, Folder 24)
    - United Packinghouse Workers of America 1954-57, undated (Box 44a, Folder 25)
    - Boston Women's Trade Union League 1933, 1948 (Box 44a, Folder 26)
    - World Federation of Trade Unions 1945-49 (Box 44a, Folder 27)
    - Women workers in a hat factory: photographs circa 1900s (Box 44a, Folder 28)
- RECENT ADDITIONS
  - Business--Executives: interviews by Mary B. Bradshaw, related correspondence and reports 1952-53 [see also SERIES V. OCCUPATIONS - Business-Executives, box 22a] (Box 44b)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - H.J. Bartle Manufacturing Corp., original mounted photographs of workers (12), circa late 19th century (Box 45)
  - "Women at Work: Views and Visions form the Pioneer Valley 1870-1945" (photographs from exhibit) (Box 46)